[music]
>> The US Israel war against Iran is in
full swing. Missile exchanges are
unfolding across the region. Energy
infrastructure is burning across
multiple fronts. There are attacks on US
bases. Markets are reacting violently
and multiple countries are suddenly
deploying military assets across the
Eastern Mediterranean here right off the
coast of Cyprus. So joining me to break
it all down is John Kiriakou, former CIA
officer
and one of the most outspoken critics of
how wars are sold to the American
public.
Let's get straight into it. John,
welcome.
Thank you, Susie. It's good to see you
again.
Always a pleasure to see you, too, John.
I hope you're doing well.
Thank you.
John
>> Thank you. Thank you. And the same to
you.
The best I'm trying to do the best that
we can here. You know, you've been
receiving texts and messages from me, so
You're under direct threat in a time of
war.
It's It's Listen, if you end up with
PTSD, it would be completely and
perfectly normal.
It's not every day that when we go to
bed at night, we have to worry about
being blown up because we happen to be
in a war zone through no fault of our
own.
Yeah. Well, Britain happen to happens to
have bases in Cyprus. There's nothing we
can do about it. It's
a part of
the creation of the Republic of Cyprus.
It's
So there's nothing we can do about it.
Anyway, we have no say in it and we just
hope and pray that the incidents that
occurred
will not follow.
Of course, there were attacks on the
British bases and not on Cyprus. So but
the British bases are based on Cyprus
land, so
they're mutually exclusive.
[clears throat] And when we say British
bases
>> That's right. I mean, I'm sorry. I'm
supposed to be interviewing you, but
just just to get the context out there.
They're not just some military bases
with barracks and
sleeping arrangements for the staff.
They occupy 3% of Cyprus land. So,
within the perimeter of the British
bases, you got
tens, if not hundreds, of Cypriot
villages and towns
and uh thousands of of Cypriot
population living within what is called
British sovereign British areas of
Cyprus.
Mhm. Yeah.
>> Outrageous. And schools which have
schools, public schools there.
Um all of last week, the citizens of
Akrotiri uh
village, which is which took which from
which the the British bases be named
after,
uh they evacuated the whole village. The
schools were closed and some went to
live with family, others went to live in
monasteries. They couldn't find refuge
anywhere else. So,
let's get into it now for
uh our American viewers, also.
John, I wanted to ask you that there are
many Americans who've lived through Iraq
and Afghanistan, and they're asking a
simple question.
How and why Washington has fundamentally
miscalculated this new war in the Middle
East?
That's really the big question.
Um
and forgive me, I'm going to give you a
very long-winded answer, but I think I
think it needs some explanation.
When George W. Bush decided to
create a reason to wage war against
Iraq,
he knew that he needed to win over
public opinion first. And he
crisscrossed the country
just repeating the lie over and over
again that Saddam Hussein had weapons of
mass destruction and that they would be
used against the United States. And Bush
was successful in winning over the the
hearts and minds of the American people.
Donald Trump has done literally nothing
to explain to Americans why this war was
necessary.
The truth of the matter is the United
States partnered with
Israel
to attack Iran
another country that poses no threat to
the United States
just because the Israelis insisted that
we do it.
I've said before on many podcasts and
I'm going to say it again.
In all the years that I was in
government, whether it was at the CIA or
at the Senate Foreign Relations
Committee and even before I entered
government going back to the 1980s,
every single Israeli prime minister that
ever came to Washington
asked every single American president
to bomb Iran. Please bomb Iran, bomb
Iran, bomb Iran and every single
president said no. And presidents have
talked about this publicly.
Obama,
George W. Bush,
Joe Biden in the form as recently
yesterday of Tony Blinken
having said the same thing that the
Israelis would demand every single time
they'd come here
to bomb Iran.
And they were always told no
until Donald Trump said yes.
Now, there are rumors that the reason he
said yes was
was that
Benjamin Netanyahu said that if Israel
were forced to act alone, they would use
nuclear weapons.
Haven't they haven't they pulled that
card that
haven't they used that before also in
the past? In the past, yes. Yes, they've
they have pulled that in the past.
But, why not call the bluff
and say, "You know what? You want to You
want to nuke Iran? Go go for it. This is
not our fight. It's not our war. You go
ahead and attack Iran with nuclear
weapons, and then you answer to the
international community. Go ahead. Go
ahead and do it."
And for what purpose?
There was a fatwa more than 20 years ago
issued by former the the late Ayatollah
Ali Khamenei
forbidding the Iranian government from
from creating a nuclear bomb.
A fatwa.
Which we don't talk about in the United
States. And there have been two, not
one, two national intelligence estimates
which are which are the final analysis
of every single organization in the
American intelligence community
determining that Iran was not building a
nuclear weapon.
It was not.
But, we bombed them anyway because the
Israelis told us to.
The Israelis have a hold on American
politics that is unprecedented.
And it's unlike anything else that we've
seen anywhere in the world.
They have lobbyists, effective lobbyists
working at every single level of
government. And if you don't tow the
Israeli line,
they will run a candidate against you in
the primary, and 80% of the time
they've won.
They will spend millions of dollars to
defeat you, no matter what office you're
running for.
And politicians don't have the guts to
stand up to them.
And so, now here we are in a war
that has almost immediately dragged the
entire region into it,
and it has caused our Arab allies to
say, "Wait a minute.
Kuwait is hosting 50,000 American ground
troops.
Saudi Arabia 15,000 American ground
troops. Bahrain is the headquarters of
the American fifth fleet.
Qatar hosts the largest American Air
Force base in the world.
And the United Arab Emirates has at
least 10,000 American ground troops at
three different bases.
And those countries were still attacked.
And they still have casualties. So, what
benefit do they have
of hosting American forces and American
troops and American fighter jets in
their countries? All they have received
is death and destruction.
One final point, Suzy.
For the United States and Israel to win,
right? To win, in air quotes,
we need to see the utter collapse and
replacement of the Iranian government.
And to see that replacement be a
pro-American, pro-Israeli Zionist
regime. That will never happen in a
million years.
>> [clears throat]
>> On the other hand,
all the Iranians need to do to win
is to survive.
That's it.
So, in my view, this is a no-win
situation for the United States and for
Israel. And instead, it is bringing only
death and destruction to the rest of the
region.
God, there's so many aspects to it. Um
one can talk for hours.
Um
>> [sighs]
>> Yeah. You You mentioned about, you know,
even in the elections, how I mean, the
when was it? In 2024, your last
elections, it's AIPAC. AIPAC themselves,
they put out this this post celebrating
that 95 It wasn't 90 or it was 90 90 90
or 95% It wasn't less
uh of the people elected in the house,
so Congress and Senate, where um
um
well, pro-AIPAC, pro-Israel
people. So,
>> Yeah. it's clear who who they're
serving. They're not serving the
American people. They're not serving the
American interests, and that's very sad.
And a recent example is Lindsey Graham.
What was the deal with him all of these
last few days? Appearing on on all these
channels, making all these statements as
if he's a president of the country, and
wearing that Cuba hat on, mentioning
that Cuba is next. I mean, the world's
gone crazy. And he's he was also calling
for deeper US military action against
Iran, and calling his South Carolina
constituents to go fight for whom? For
whom? I need your comments on this
>> because Americans I'm I'm happy to see
that or or is it me getting the wrong
impression, wrong idea all the way from
here? You tell me if I'm wrong, but I
think Americans are waking up. The
general public is waking up because
there's also there's also
a polls taking place and and have come
out saying that
>> [snorts]
>> this war has got the lowest support from
the American public from all the wars
that America has ever been involved in.
So,
just just your comments on these
cuz we need your feedback here.
>> So,
there are two two polls that have come
out in the last 3 days that show 27%
in the one poll and 4% in the other poll
of Americans support the war. So, the
vast majority of Americans this war. So,
when you come right to it, in 2016, this
is one of the important reasons that
Donald Trump got elected president
because
we were involved in these forever wars.
We had transitioned into a full-time
wartime economy,
and the Democrats were just as pro-war
as the Republicans. And so, the
Republican Party split to the
traditional neo-conservative side
embodied by John McCain, who is at the
head and Lindsey Graham who I call her
majesty Lindsey
Graham.
On the other side the Democrats were
pro-war.
And so there was a large anti-war
faction in the American electorate and
they voted for Trump because Donald
Trump promised no new wars.
And so we got through the first
the first term without any new wars
although he did kill
two senior Iranian intelligence and
military officials in Iraq.
He did wage war in Syria but these were
seen more as counter-terrorism
operations.
Um
somehow
Donald Trump forgot who he was and he
forgot what his constituents were
demanding. And so Donald Trump
every Republican every Democrat before
him decided that war pretty good.
And we could use a little bit of an
economic boost and so he was going to
wage war alongside the Israelis.
Again, he's you know Trump
person is such that he needs
glorification
constant glorification. One thing about
Donald Trump's personality is that he
craves glorification.
Um
For example, in the in the middle of the
night
he added his name to the John F. Kennedy
Center for the Performing Arts. One of
the most beautiful buildings in in the
entire country. So now it says the
Donald J. Trump and John F. Kennedy
Center for the Performing Arts. He
is holding up highway funds unless
we change the name of our airport from
Dulles International Airport to the
Donald J. Trump International Airport.
He won't He won't allow New York City to
complete its subway tunnel unless they
change the name George Washington Bridge
to the Donald J. Trump Bridge.
Uh it's it's
It's ego maniacal.
>> We know this about his personality. But
um what I'm wondering is But my But my
point though related to the personality
though is that
real glory to him can only come with
war.
He can only go down in history books as
the president who overthrew the Iranian
government when every other president
since Jimmy Carter failed. That he was
the that overthrew the Iranian
government and he brought peace and
prosperity to the Middle East and now
it's the land of milk and honey and
everybody's going to live happily ever
after.
The reason why we're we're already
bogged down
is because he truly believed
that as soon as we fired the first shot,
the whole Iranian government would
collapse like a house of cards because
these wealthy Ira- Iranian Americans,
mostly in Southern California, most of
whom happen to be Jewish, convinced him
that the whole was a house of cards.
And that it was so unstable
the first rocket would make the whole
thing fall apart and it didn't. It
didn't and they're not afraid of our
missiles and they have 92 million people
and the country is the size of all of
Western Europe.
And so what are you going to keep
launching pinprick missile attacks
because they can take those for the next
100 years? Yeah.
>> Or you going to put boots on the ground
and then tell Americans to expect 10,000
dead soldiers in the next 6 months?
So now we're stuck.
Um
>> [cough]
>> there's also the video circulating
recent footage by the Sun in the UK
showing the Iranian missiles emerging
from underground silos that are
completely like you can't tell it's a
desert. There's no even like there's
nothing to tell that below that there's
anything, you know, and um
>> [snorts]
>> the the the announcement they made
yesterday from Iran that uh future
launches will carry warheads exceeding 1
ton.
Uh future attacks each war each uh
missile will be carrying warheads
exceeding um 1 ton. I mean, for 20 years
the US
uh failed to defeat the the the
the Tal Taliban in um Afghanistan when
all they were hiding in the mountains
and in the caves were AK-47s and RPG
launchers and, you know, hidden weapon
caches. So, how are they going to how
are they going to defeat this? We're not
talking about RPGs and AK-47s.
How how realistic I mean, of course, you
can bomb bomb an underground facility
just like they did with um Nasrallah,
but you need to know where it is and
they don't know where these ones are.
No, they don't know. They don't know.
That's why they had to use a 30-ton bomb
uh last year when uh when bombing Iran
because they had an idea where it was,
they weren't sure if there was anything
[clears throat] in it, and then Trump,
being Trump, said last year that the
entire Iranian nuclear program had been
obliterated. That was his word,
obliterated. So, either he lied,
he was tricked,
or he's too stupid to know that he
wasn't able to obliterate it. Yeah,
because you
>> And now we're in a war.
>> If it's been obliterated, then why are
you stating now that you're going to you
you've you've gone to this war because
they were days away from producing a
nuclear weapon, which is something we've
been hearing for 30 days from Bibi's
mouth.
>> You know, there's a video there's a
video going around.
>> Exactly. There's a video going around of
every time Netanyahu said on the floor
of the United States Congress.
>> it. That
that uh Iran is 6 months away from the
nuclear bomb.
>> and it reaches Yeah, yeah. Uh-huh.
Yeah.
>> Uh-huh.
I think Americans Americans are now
coming to realization of this though.
We're aware of these lies. Yes.
You know, there's a kind of a mystery
going on right now, too, Susie, as to
where exactly Netanyahu is. Yes.
>> There were reports that he was in
Germany, he was hiding in Germany. I
heard today he's hiding in Cyprus.
Wherever he happens to be, he's hiding.
You know, what kind of wartime leader is
that?
Yeah.
Well, I mean, they seem to to be on the
on his tracks a whole lot now. I mean,
they seem to know I mean
It's It's kind of like they're using his
playbook now, you know? I don't know how
they've managed. Maybe it's the Russians
fe- feeding them like the satellite
reconnaissance and targeting
intelligence. I don't know if if it's
from the Russians or they've managed to
infiltrate with their agents like just
like they did
you know, the Israeli state, but um they
did hit his house. They did target his
house and his brother was in in his
house and his brother is dead.
Um [snorts] they are employing Israel's
tactics of, you know, taking out taking
out the heads, the leadership, because
they've also targeted Ben-Gvir's house
and Ben-Gvir, I don't know what is the
latest, but up until
last night, the reports was that he was
seriously injured.
Critically injured. So, they're now
employing Israel's tactics.
They are. It's the same tactic.
Yes.
And And this has to this has to have
the Israelis on their on their heel, you
know? They I don't think that they
expected any of this. No.
I think that these that the It was the
Israelis who convinced Trump that Iran
was a house of cards.
That the Israelis did that because they
actually believe themselves.
Well, they I mean they wanted to use the
the they only have a
limited time left up until the midterm
elections and everyone all the analysts
are saying even you that this is a last
big opportunity to take out Iran because
they're getting the feedback that the
American public has had it this time. So
Yes. Time was running and they also have
their fall I think Israel there's also
fall elections in Israel. But um
Yes. To Trump to for for that matter
Trump came out yesterday. I mean you see
him with the press he's making all these
like co- crazy crazy ass statements.
They're asking him about the Tomahawks
and he's like I don't know maybe I sold
them Tomahawks. I don't know. And then
he was making these he was throwing um
Steve Whitkoff What's the name of his
son-in-law? God. Kushner. Jared Kushner.
Yes and he threw them under the bus
saying, "You know, they gave me the info
and that's why I decided to you know
call call the war and it was based on
info that and he he named them and he
threw them under the bus. So
I mean where does Jared Kushner come
into this anyway? He doesn't hold an
official position within the government.
So you're saying out publicly that
God, you're going by Jared Kushner's
suggestions that Iran is going to attack
us soon?
That's what you're telling the American
public? That's why you entered this war?
And let me let me add something too. The
Russians made a statement today that
made perfect sense. The Russians said
that they will no longer engage in
uh settlement talks with the Ukrainians
that are that are headed by the United
States because the United States can't
be trusted. It was engaged supposedly in
talks with Iran pretending to go through
talks with Iran and then they attacked
Iran.
So the Russians said why should we trust
the Americans to broker talks with
Ukraine when they could just as soon
turn around and attack us in the middle
of the talks. And I think that's exactly
right. Yeah, I mean I mean
the two wars with Iran happened in the
middle of the so-called discussions that
America was having with Iran on the on
its nuclear program. So, I mean they
can't be trusted anymore. And
Trump did reach out behind the scenes
twice in these 10 days for a ceasefire
with the Iranians and they sent they
played some kind
>> we've we've been told, yeah.
>> said no Well, Bibi didn't like it and he
was he was calling over at the White
House to see if these reports were true,
right? I mean, what does this
What does this show? Who's running the
show? Who's Who's the president of
America?
Or is the president of America president
of America or or is he representing
whose interests is he representing?
>> Honestly, honestly, on foreign policy
on foreign policy, Benjamin Netanyahu
has just as much authority as whoever
happens to be president of the United
States.
We've conceded foreign policy to the
Israelis and to Israeli interests.
But John, it seems that they that the
Americans are
inclined into asking for, you know,
getting into
back-channel talks for a ceasefire and
they're seeing it's not working. It It
seems that Trump has called Putin and
asked asked for Putin's help on this.
Is this true? Have we heard anything?
>> I I I haven't heard that, but I wouldn't
be surprised.
>> So, this was this was the reporting
coming in from Thanasis Avgerinos. He's
a very well-respected, very
well-connected our Greek reporter based
in Moscow. And this was his reporting
late last night on a big Greek
channels.
That [snorts] the report he has from the
Kremlin is that Donald Trump reached out
to Putin for him to intervene to
hopefully broker a ceasefire with Iran
because Iran isn't isn't
isn't having it. The his two attempts so
far, they they turned them down.
So, this is a report that's come out.
>> [sighs]
>> Yeah, I believe that. And And I'll tell
you what, the the Russians have been
giving the Iranians targeting
information.
Um that was leaked a few days ago.
And I remember reading it and and just
saying to a friend, "Well, of course
they're giving the Iranians targeting
information. They're allies. We're
giving the Ukrainians targeting
information."
The The Russians gave the North
Vietnamese targeting information. We
gave the Afghan Mujahideen targeting
information and Stinger missiles. This
is what enemies do to one another.
So, what's the best way to to get that
to stop? You just reach out directly to
the Russians and say, "Please stop. Help
us negotiate some kind of a ceasefire."
Oh, let's see if it's true. I But I But
I'll I'll add one other thing, Suzy.
We Here in the United States, we look
like fools.
We look like puppets of the Israelis,
and we look like fools for being duped
into another yet another war of choice.
The 27 uh US military facilities across
the region have been struck, even in
Cherlik airbase in Turkey, which is one
of the key hubs for US air power for the
whole Middle East for decades has been
hit and rendered um unusable, while
several ports that the US uses in the
Gulf have also been damaged. Even the
the port that the US was building in
Oman because they wanted to stop using
the port in in Dubai because of exposure
and stuff. Even that has been struck.
So, now the US seems to be relying
heavily on the ports of in Europe and in
India to ship equipment over. So, what
does it I want your comment on this,
please.
Yeah, see, this is yet another one of
those examples of the United States just
never thought would happen and so didn't
prepare for. India is far from the war
zone. It's far and it's hard to get from
India to the Persian Gulf.
Uh but this is
exactly what we should have expected.
The Iranians told us in advance that
this would quickly escalate into a
regional war. It did almost immediately
and then the Iranians told us that they
would close the Strait of Hormuz.
They're in the process of of
closing the Strait of Hormuz. This
morning they attacked three ships, uh
two oil tankers and one cargo ship.
Like what
What did we think was going to happen?
They told us what was going to happen.
Yeah. And we just pretended not to hear.
So since you've touched upon that, the
economic cost of the war to America is
how much per day? I'm getting I'm I'm
reading reports that it could be 800
million dollars a day and then I'm
reading other reports that could be up
to 2 billion dollars a day. So do you
have a a clearer idea?
Yeah, Axios reported um
2 days ago I think it was that it was
between 2 and 3 billion dollars a day
and it reminded me of a story not a
story. It reminded me of of an of an
incident where I was working I was
working at the CIA during the
uh Kuwait
Iraq uh war and it was right before we
began the liberation of Kuwait and I
remember the president's morning briefer
coming back to the office and saying
that the president was shocked to
speechless
when they told him that we were spending
100 million dollars a day
in the Gulf. Well, 100 million back
then, yeah.
100 million Well, just with inflation
it's going to be close to 2 billion.
>> Yes.
And um there's there's
I mean there's this all all these
repercussions, right? We're seeing um
something extraordinary happening.
Yesterday, you know, oil prices had
surged towards the $115 um
>> [snorts]
>> per barrel mark, and then they suddenly
dropped before suddenly be right before
the markets closed. You see President
Trump calling CBS News to declare that
the war was pretty much uh complete.
The markets reacted immediately, and you
know, correcting themselves, and but
simultaneously the defense secretary, he
told 60 Minutes simultaneously that the
war might only be in the beginning. So,
before we go go into the matter of, you
know, um
two completely different um um
perspectives on the same war by
two people
who are on in daily contact, possibly
hourly contact, about the war.
I mean, what does
what does this say about the president
effectively moving global markets
through wartime messaging? Just picking
up the phone just to rectify the markets
just for the day, and
your take.
I think that's I think that's exactly
what he did. But, you can only do that
once, twice, maybe possibly three times
before people just don't believe
anything you say anymore. And and so
long as you continue doing what you say
you're not doing, or say that you're
going to soon stop doing, the markets
are going to stop reacting.
>> [cough and clears throat]
>> And um
what say does um J.D. Vance have in all
this? And Tulsi Gabbard, because is it
true that they're the only two people
closest to the president who were firmly
opposing this war?
Yeah, it was my understanding that it
was Tulsi Gabbard, J.D. Vance, and
and General Keane, the the chairman of
the Joint Chiefs of Staff, which which
is which is quite common. Usually the
joint chiefs uh chiefs of staff are the
last ones that want to go to war.
Um and and that's it doesn't matter
who's in the White House. They're always
that way because they know how terrible
war is.
Um Tulsi Gabbard I fear has been
marginalized and pushed off to the side.
Uh to tell you the truth, I think Marco
Rubio is really running American foreign
and defense policy.
And and I think that he's doing this not
just because he's a neo-conservative
that he really believes this stuff. Of
course he believes it. But there's so
much talk in Washington about about the
very young, relatively inexperienced
J.D. Vance being Trump's choice to uh to
replace him.
I don't think that's true. I think Marco
Rubio is going to be the Republican
nominee for president and I think Rubio
is doing a lot of this
just so that he can stake his claim as
the Republican frontrunner before J.D.
Vance gets his footing.
Well, I mean if if Vance continues
opposing this war behind closed doors in
the Oval Office, then this is most
certainly going to happen.
Yeah. So I think so, too. I mean, do you
find the calls These are not These are
calls on
growing discussions online about
invoking the 25th? And people are really
concerned. Americans are really
concerned about invoking the 25th which
would allow for J.D. Vance to assume
presidential authority. You you know,
claiming the president is no longer able
to perform
perform his duties. Um do you find these
calls gaining traction? I mean, for it
to happen, even if if the vast majority
of the population asks for it, it needs
Congress to okay it. So, I don't see it.
I mean, do you find some Do you find
logic behind them?
No.
>> Rational? No. They would have to No,
they would have to determine that he's
mentally ill and unable to uh to carry
out his duties as president. You you
can't invoke the 25th just because you
don't like somebody's policies. And we
have had two presidents with dementia.
Joe Biden most recently, who clearly was
demented. He was demented during the
campaign. And then before him, Ronald
Reagan.
Um
And and no seriously
considered invoking the 25th Amendment.
So no
it's thinking on the part of Democrats.
It's just not going to happen.
John, I [clears throat] want to go now
to
uh the area again, the region here.
And um Iran's Foreign Ministry
Foreign Ministry has warned about what
it says are Israeli false flag
operations
across the region citing the incidents
in Azerbaijan, in Cyprus. They also
cited that they're they're insisting
that yes, the drone the British saying
that the drone that hit the the drone
that hit the British bases in Cyprus did
not leave Iran, but
it left Lebanon. But the Iranians are
saying that still it wasn't an Iranian
drone. It was a false flag by the
Israelis. Anyway, we know that Israel is
occupying chunks of Southern Lebanon. So
>> [snorts]
>> you wouldn't expect I mean the truth is
somewhere there.
Depends on who you want to believe. But
anyway, the Iranians are coming out
saying that um there are these are all
false flag incidents. Azerbaijan,
Cyprus, and Turkey, they were falsely
attributed to Iran. And we have seen
false flags being uncovered when the
Saudi and UAE authorities detained
Mossad linked operatives connected to
the attacks on their infrastructure,
specifically Aramco, which was [snorts]
initially attributed to Iran. They are
doing their best to make it to drag it
to drag countries into this make it into
a regional war. And these are false
flags that luckily so far
um
were why um acted upon. So this is quite
scary. They're not going to give up. I
mean, there's there's
there's info now, you know, about
warning about in the US there are all
these sleep
sleeper cells and
maybe something could happen in the US.
So, how worried are you that
you know, maybe even in the US something
would happen that would be linked to
Iran, but it's not really Iran that's
behind it, but it's Israel that's behind
it.
So, I'm very fearful of Israeli false
flags. The Israelis have been carrying
out false flag operations since the
founding of the state of Israel, and
they're usually very good at it. Uh
there are some legendary stories that
they taught us at the CIA about
wonderful, creative, innovative false
flag operations that had been carried
out by the Israeli Mossad. Um as soon as
we started seeing some of these attacks,
you know, on the Saudi oil field, on
Azerbaijan, on Cyprus, my first thought
was
it was that they were Israeli false
flags. What scares me the most is that
the Israelis may try to attack the
Al-Aqsa Mosque in Jerusalem and blame it
on on the Arabs
or blame it on the Iranians. I mean,
Iranians Shia Muslims don't necessarily
believe that Al-Aqsa as as a building is
third holiest site. They believe that
the site is up in the sky. It's in
heaven.
But
we know that the Israelis want to
destroy Al-Aqsa. There are entire
factions of the Israeli electorate that
publicly advocate destroying Al-Aqsa and
building the third temple.
So, this just has
this just has war written all over it,
and I think that Israeli false flags are
so prevalent, so so dangerous that we
all need to be on the lookout for them.
John, do you think they they they would
also maybe do a perform a false flag on
US territory, blame it on the Iranian
sleeper cells just to get US boots on
the ground if at all possible? How can
How can anyone even fathom US boots on
the ground in that country? In that vast
country, 92 million population. Do you
think Do you think that is a possibility
that they are even entertaining?
Are you fearful of that?
God, I hate to say it. Yes, I am fearful
and yes, I think they are entertaining.
And I only say that because after
promise after promise
that there would be no American boots on
the ground, both President Trump and
Secretary of Defense Hegseth have said
that we are at least planning for that
as a contingency measure.
I think that would be a death sentence
for thousands of Americans.
You know, I was on Fox News the other
night because there was there was a leak
and I'm sure that it was a it was an
authorized leak that the United States
is in talks with the Iranian Kurds to
use the Kurds as the front-line boots on
the ground.
And they asked me, you know, if this was
possible. I said, "Sure, it's it's
possible. The United States has long had
very warm and friendly relations with
Iraq's Kurds and with Syria's Kurds.
Not necessarily with Iran's Kurds
because there's no contact really.
Excuse me. And certainly no relationship
at all with Turkey's Kurds. But
the Iranian Kurds hate the central
government. It's just that there's
nothing they can do about it. If they
were to
begin moving toward Tehran, they would
be they would be obliterated by the
Iranian military. You know, I suppose if
the if the goal is to draw out Kurds
onto the open battlefield so that the
Iranian Air Force can bomb them, that's
one thing. But
Iran's Kurds are not going to liberate
the country and overthrow this
government for the American
and the Israeli governments. Yeah, I
mean there's been talk about that and
about America wanting to arm them and
fund them, but isn't that a bit too late
and isn't that a bit
hard to do logistically? I mean of
course it could be done through Turkey,
but I don't know if Turkey wouldn't
allow it, seriously.
I don't know if you want to explain to
the people why.
>> Turkey Turkey has to live in that
neighborhood. They don't want to provoke
the Iranians unnecessarily. That's that
doesn't make any sense for for Turkish
policy. The Turks would get nothing out
of that.
>> don't want the Kurds to end up setting
up their own, which is their
their their
>> Exactly.
>> dream also to have their own state, the
state of Kurdistan. They've been
always opposing it and that's the reason
why they also subjugated the Kurds in
Syria once Trump withdrew his support of
them in 2020, his financial and arms
support of them when they did all the
work for for Trump. They they were
fighting ISIS on his behalf. Once they
got that done,
>> [snorts]
>> of course ISIS reemerged
now with Julani, but
anyway. So he withdrew his support of
them. Turkey Turkey infiltrated the
northern part of Syria where the Kurds
are and has occupied it since because he
doesn't want a a strong Kurdish
population to set up a
Kurdish state. So it's very hard. Israel
wants to open that second front for Iran
so that they are busy
and
not focus on the one front, but it's
it's very hard for America and Israel to
do that with the Iranians and with
[snorts] the Kurds in Iran, right?
>> It's very
It's very hard. It's very hard because
you're right.
Listen, I I'm a long time supporter of
the Kurds and I believe that the Kurds
deserve an independent Kurdistan.
But it's just not
going to happen.
It's not going to happen because no
regional power, no great power is going
to allow it to happen.
There was very briefly an independent
Kurdistan in northern Iraq
from 1946 [clears throat]
to 1949. That was it.
The Iraqi Kurds now have autonomy, which
is great because half of the country's
oil reserves are are in Kurdish
territory. So they make some money.
But nobody's going to get an independent
Kurdistan.
And the Iranian Kurds have never even
like approached a point
where they may declare Yeah. Um
uh independence.
So no. See, but this is another This is
another example of
of Donald Trump, Marco Rubio, Pete
Hegseth underestimating
the Iranian government and the Iranian
people in that
they believe that Kurds are Kurds are
Kurds.
And so if we're friendly with the
Iranian Sorry, if we're friendly with
the Iraqi Kurds and the Syrian Kurds,
then the Iranian Kurds are going to love
us and they're going to do what we say.
And oh look, our bombing didn't
overthrow the Iranian government, but
that's okay cuz the Kurds will do it for
us. No. And it's like no, the Kurds
won't do it for you. Yeah. It's too
late. It's been I think it's been many
years when
um correct um
um secret service uh briefings were held
with the US president um or any US
president over the last few years. Um
I mean the the the at least with the
case with the with Trump, uh he's been
surrounded by people who are promoting a
obviously someone else's agenda. Even
Tucker mentioned it the other day. He
said that on a personal level he visited
Trump uh he paid a visit to Trump in
Washington. It was a Monday or Tuesday
right before the war was about to start
cuz he could tell the war was about to
start. He wanted to talk him out of it.
And then even when the war started,
Tucker said he tried contacting Trump,
and they just wouldn't give it give him
Trump on the phone. They told him,
"Look, forget about it. He's just locked
up in that room, and they're showing him
all these polls that are giving him all
these numbers that there's a 9 to 10
chance that he's going to win the war."
So,
uh
You know what? Let me Let me comment on
that if I may because I have a little
bit of inside information I can pass on.
So, I have a friend who works in the
Republican National Committee.
And he told me more than a month ago
that the internal
secret
Republican National Committee polls show
what he called a bloodbath
against the Republicans. That was before
the war.
>> War.
Donald Trump Talking about the midterms.
rolled the dice. He was mention he would
The midterms. It's the midterms, okay.
Yes, the midterms. Donald Trump
rolled the dice thinking, "If I can
collapse this Iranian government, I'm
going to be a hero, and the polls are
going to jump up for the Republicans,
and it's going to be, you know, it's
going to be a historic advantage and a
historic turnaround for the Republican
Party." Well, exactly the opposite has
happened.
Now,
the polls are so dire because we're
bogged down in a war that we can't
possibly win.
Now, instead of losing 15
seats and flipping control to the
Democrats, Oh, it's control of the House
of Representatives, they're looking at
40 to 50 seats. Yeah, overall. And now
for the first time they're looking at
losing the Senate as well.
So, this was a disaster
and a terrible, terrible decision.
So, uh
Americans need to understand that
opposing this war, am I right to say
this, is not about left versus right? If
you're a Republican and you're opposing
this war, doesn't make you a left
Democrat, doesn't make you a liberal.
It's about interventionists versus
non-interventionists, right? It's about
America first, not Israel first.
>> Yes, that's exactly right. We're having
this very odd realignment politically in
the United States right now, Suzy, where
members of the progressive left and
members of the Make America Great Again,
the MAGA right, are coming together on
this issue because neither one of them
want war.
Who would have thought? This is
unprecedented in American history. It's
like the communists and the fascists
joining forces Yes. uh to
to oppose war.
I mean, I'm I'm exaggerating a little
bit, of course, because progressives
aren't communists and MAGAs aren't
fascists, most of them aren't. So,
it's it's astounding to me that the
Republican and Democratic Party
leaderships have not realized that
they're losing their own people
on this issue. The American people don't
want war.
We had decades of uninterrupted wars
that we ended up losing in the end.
We're bankrupt as a country, our roads
are our airports look like they
belong in the third world. We have
bridges that are falling into the rivers
below them, and I want to know why the
Chinese have trains that go 500 km an
hour, and I have to go on a train I
could walk faster than some of the
trains that we have in the United
States. Man, the money
the money
Why do the Chinese get all these things?
Because the Exactly, they don't on war.
And the money you spend on all these
wars you could have had free health care
for everyone and the best the best
education system and no homeless people
no vets being homeless all these
veterans being homeless that's shameful
shameful.
Um It is and and we have we have
veterans every literally every single
day committing suicide many of them
committing suicide in the parking lots
of the Veterans Administration hospitals
that refuse to treat them for
post-traumatic stress disorder.
Very sad.
It's something like as many as six a day
kill themselves in the Veterans
Administration hospital parking lots.
Yeah.
Well, the lobbyists don't care about
that neither does AIPAC. John I wanted I
wanted to I wanted to touch also on
Lebanon. You know that is that that is
my fatherland. So there's
Lebanon is also
very very
worse on the situation there. Yes, there
is the supposed ceasefire signed back in
the end of 2024. Israel never kept up to
to its terms of the ceasefire. They
never stopped bombing South Lebanon.
Since then until February 28th, they had
killed through their
attacks and their their bombings
hundreds of Lebanese civilians. They
never stopped
also using what do you say
white phosphorus which Amnesty
International uh
deems it's it's I mean it's not a legal
means of war. It causes long-term
injuries severe burns and destruction of
farmland. We know why they doing that
since people are not
deserting South Lebanon. They [snorts]
want to destroy their livelihood so that
they do end up deserting South Lebanon
and the latest is that
Israel has issued
what do you say a directive that 53
villages and towns of South Lebanon
needed to be evacuated. And
the sad
truth of the matter is, as we speak,
300,000 Lebanese from South Lebanon have
acted upon those orders, descending upon
Beirut and other parts of Lebanon,
living in tents or in their cars or with
family.
>> [snorts]
[sighs]
>> So,
and they've killed since March 1st,
hundreds of civilians, 85 of them being
children.
How realistic is the Greater Israel
project today as we speak? As
As As far as Lebanon is concerned?
Yeah, I think that the Israelis have
guaranteed that Lebanon will be a failed
state. I don't think any Israeli
government is going to allow
Lebanon to flourish as a nation.
I think we will continue to see Israeli
attacks, Israeli forced displacement of
civilians. I read a statistic yesterday
that by the end of the week, as many as
700,000 Lebanese will be internally
displaced.
This is a
humanitarian disaster. And And the
world, most of the world isn't focused
on it because they're all watching
what's unfolding in Iran.
Well, Lebanon already doesn't have
enough food, enough medical care, enough
enough clean water. It's It's only going
to get worse. So,
take that and couple it with these these
incredibly provocative statements made
by the by the fascist evangelical
American ambassador to Israel, Mike
Huckabee, to Tucker Carlson 2 weeks ago,
that he has no problem with Greater
Israel and said, quote, they should just
take it. And what What he meant by it
was all Arab land from the Euphrates
River to the Nile. Just take it. He
doesn't care.
So, if that's the attitude of the of the
representative of the president of the
United States,
then I think we should all be living in
fear.
Um
I wanted
to ask you
before we close this, how do you see
this ending? I mean, not the war as
such, but all this like um
thing we're living under, you know,
Greater Israel and all this threat of
Greater Israel and it's becoming more
and more realistic. And up until a few
years ago, it was just like, "Oh, you're
a conspiracy theorist for even
mentioning it." But it's all out in the
open now. They're making public
statements about it.
Netanyahu has
been caught on camera publicly stating
that it's his lifelong ambition. When
the [snorts] war started, he he he was
so happy to speak on camera and saying,
"This has been 40 years in the making
for me, a dream for me."
>> [snorts]
>> The war with Iran because Iran is their
last um um
uh what do you say? Um
thing
stopping them from realizing the Greater
Israel project. Well, Iran and Turkey,
which is why Naftali Bennett, the former
Israeli Prime Minister, is also now
saying, "After Iran, it's Turkey.
Turkey's next." So, what is how do you
see all this ending? I mean, do you see
them realizing these goals because they
they weren't so close to realizing them
a few years ago, but now it's it's all,
you know, unraveling.
I don't see them succeeding. There are
too many Arabs. There are too many
Muslims.
There are too many people who oppose
this this
naked
Israeli aggression.
Um I don't even
care.
Well, I shouldn't say I don't care
because I care [clears throat] very
much, but I don't think it matters even
if the United States were to support
such a crazy position. And and the
United States wouldn't support such a
crazy position. Um, Mike Huckabee is is
a fluke in the system. But they have
been supported by John. They have. I
mean, they're they're Not not a not a
greater Israel. The the But
what are all these wars that the US have
been doing has been doing over the last
25 years?
The seven nations that um BB kept saying
that they need to get out out of the way
to topple their regimes. They've they've
reached the seventh nation. So, who has
done those wars on their behalf? It's
America who's done wars on their behalf.
Look at them independently though. Libya
was no threat to Israel. Never. Never
was. Never would be. Uh Libya was was a
thorn in the side of the United States.
The the US didn't overthrow and kill
Gaddafi for Israel. We did it for
ourselves. Same in Somalia. Somalia's no
threat to Israel
at all. Never was. Um, they were a
threat to the United States or to at
least to American commerce.
>> [clears throat]
>> Excuse me. Um, Afghanistan?
I mean, that was for a while that was a
righteous war. It was a war uh to
destroy Al-Qaeda. It morphed into
something that was wrong. It morphed
into this never-ending war against the
Taliban who had never attacked the
United States, but in the beginning that
was a righteous war. We had to destroy
Al-Qaeda. It's not that the Israelis
wanted us to.
Um, it certainly was in Israel's
interest, but that was the United States
all the way.
You know, listen, I I am not a fan of
Israel. I am even less of a fan of
Israeli leadership, but we can't blame
all of our problems on Israel. We can
blame the United States for its for its
mistakes, too. Mhm.
Well, on Libya I I I beg to because it
was Gaddafi and him making the
announcement that, you know, he's going
to
um unhook the um
petrol
Yeah, yeah, that's what I'm saying. from
uh dollar.
>> that's what I'm saying. That was a That
was a threat to the American economy. We
didn't need the Israelis to egg us on to
overthrow Gaddafi.
Well, I mean, the Israelis were also uh
um
purporting that he was funding uh
so-called Arab terrorists and stuff. So,
and and it Yeah. Bibi has been on record
naming the seven nations.
>> [cough and clears throat]
>> They They've had a strong
a strong grip on your politicians for
sure for the last 30 years, John.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, of course. No, I I'm
not denying that American-Israeli
interests intersect. I'm just saying
that that these seven countries on the
list,
while some of them absolutely are
enemies of of Israel,
um the US had in their own national
interests reasons to overthrow them.
Understood. Okay. Now, my last question,
a very concerning one.
The Samson option. I mean, I'm I'm sure
everyone's everyone thinks it's not
going to happen. It's very far-fetched,
but um with with them in power now, Bibi
and everyone, I mean, you can't tell.
So,
I mean, do how
how plausible do you think they would
were
they would use it if Israel believed
that it was
close to losing this very important war
for itself or losing support from
America on this war,
>> [snorts]
>> uh would they resort to that?
The new use of nuclear weapons as a last
resort.
If the Israelis
believed that the state of Israel was
untenable because of, you know, Arab
advances, for example, that there were
Arab or Iranian threats that could lead
eventually even
to the end of the state of Israel. Yes,
I think they would use the Samson
option. You know, I I gave an interview
yesterday in which I said
that even a year ago I would have said
that was ridiculous.
It was it was
it was
a a
doom
uh ideology.
And now I I have to say
that yeah, I I believe the Israelis
would would carry this out. If they
really believed they were in threat of
collapse, yes,
they would take everybody out with them.
And analysts say, even though the
Israelis have never have never
acknowledged the existence of a
of a nuclear uh program or nuclear
arsenal, analysts tell us that they have
between 80 and 200 warheads.
That's enough to kill everybody.
Everybody.
Yeah.
Very scary.
Uh one last uh question, your thoughts
on the um
rapid accumulation of all this this
military build-up in Cyprus. You have
Spain, you know of them.
Um Spain has uh deployed um
a
uh frigate, and Italy has deployed um
the
another air air defense frigate.
France has deployed the um
aircraft carrier, what is it? Uh Charles
de Gaulle, with uh frigate Languedoc,
and advanced anti-missile anti-drone
systems to Cyprus.
>> [snorts]
>> Greece has deployed um two frigates,
Kimon and Psara. Kimon is considered
among the most technologically advanced
frigates currently in operational
service worldwide. Four F-16 fighter
jets and an Hellenic Air Force C-130
transport aircraft.
The United Kingdom is sending over HMS
Dragon. This is like uh What is it
today? 9 days after the attack, the
drone attack on their bases, they're
still going to send the HMS Dragon. They
have serious problem with their
military. I mean, the finances with
their military is down the hole.
Netherlands also has sent over a
frigate. And over the last over a matter
of um just 6 days, this small island in
the corner of the Mediterranean Sea has
seen the most high-level visits
we've ever seen in the matter of I don't
know, we haven't seen them maybe ever in
even in the span of a year. We've had
the Greek Defense Minister visit Cyprus
March 3rd with the top grad brass of the
Greek Army to coordinate their defense
planning with the Cypriot counterparts.
March 5th, the UK Defense Minister
visits Cyprus to meet with his uh
Cypriot counterpart. Uh March 6th,
Friday, the President of the I President
of the Republic of Cyprus met with MI6
Chief Alex Younger at the Presidential
Palace. And on Monday, March 9th, Mac
Emmanuel Macron and Greek Prime Minister
Kyriakos Mitsotakis visited Cyprus
for consultations. Just your word on
what's happening and why.
As bad
a policy as this is,
the NATO militaries and even more
broadly the European Union militaries
feel compelled
to at least
have the appearance of being supportive
of Israel
and the United States.
And so,
behind closed doors, they probably
sighed deeply and said,
>> [sighs]
>> "Well,
let's send a frigate or two frigates or
a battleship or a hospital ship and at
least make it look like we're trying to
do our part." I think that's
that's what it comes down to.
Um
which is funny to me because the Spanish
Prime Minister made some of the
strongest anti-war statements out there.
And the next thing you know, they're
sending a frigate.
>> The next day he's sending the frigate
out there.
>> Exactly. You said something a minute ago
that I think deserves a little bit of
exploration.
There was this statement recently
about Turkey
being the next big enemy of Israel that
Israel is going to have to confront. But
Turkey's a NATO country.
So, what happens
if Israel attacks Turkey?
The United States has to come in
on the side of Turkey. They have to
invoke Article 5 of NATO.
>> It's Will they? They have to invoke
Article Article 5 of NATO. They're
they're obligated by treaty
to come in on the side of Turkey and
fight against Israel.
Okay.
>> Now, will they is an entirely different
question. Yeah, because let's not forget
who
>> didn't Mhm.
Of course. And if they didn't, and I
think that they wouldn't No, that would
be the end of NATO. Yeah.
John, I know I said that was the last
question, but I'm getting another
question in by my producer, and he's
right. I need to ask you because it's
like if someone would know, John would
know being he was in this in the Secret
Service. Because here in Cyprus we've
always wanted to know
To the best of your ability, are there
nuclear weapons being stored in the
British bases in Cyprus?
That's a great question. I don't know.
But I would I would guess
>> Bible, you don't know? Um
Pardon me? Bible, you don't know?
>> Or kisses
>> Bible, I don't know.
No, I I honestly honestly, as God is my
witness, I don't know. Um I don't even
know where the American nuclear weapons
uh are based. The those are highly
guarded secrets in the ministries of
defense.
Um I would guess probably yes.
But I don't know.
Okay. John, as always,
my friend, thank you for your honesty.
Good to see you. And for helping us
understand what's really happening
behind the headlines.
Thank you.
It's an ugly situation out there. Thanks
for having me. Yeah.
We'll hope to speak to you again soon,
my friend.
I look forward to it. Bye-bye. Thank you
for watching. A small request on my
part. The channel is so close to 10,000
subscribers. I need your help to get us
there.
It just takes 2 seconds. Just subs- hit
subscribe and tap the bell. That's the
best way to support Unfiltered with Sam.
This is
uh the only English-language uh woman-
uh led geopolitical interview platform
broadcasting from the Eastern
Mediterranean. So, subscribe, share, and
help this voice uh reach further. From
here in Cyprus, this is Unfiltered with
Sam. Until next time.
>> [music]
[music]